<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nick Christie</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nick Christie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Presenting the Pipe</title>
      <link>/post/2022-03-21-presenting-the-pipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-03-21-presenting-the-pipe/</guid>
      <description>It’s a baffling thing at first.And then,once you get the hang of it,you can’t seem to imagine doing anything in another way.The %&amp;gt;% in R is just darn nifty.
So what’s the deal with the pipe?
In the process of working with your data, you are going to have a series of steps you perform to get to the final product.For example,you might start out with a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather data with R</title>
      <link>/post/2022-03-07-weather-data-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-03-07-weather-data-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Last week I read a paper: “Weathering cash flow shocks” by Brown et al. (2021) which cleverly used unexpected severe winter weather as a setting to examine shocks to firm cash flow and the effect these cash flow shocks have on utilizing and increasing credit lines.
The authors scrape decades worth of publicly available weather station data from across the United States to identify abnormal snow cover in counties where firm headquarters are located.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Introduction to R</title>
      <link>/learn/quick-introduction-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learn/quick-introduction-to-r/</guid>
      <description>WORK IN PROGRESS!
There are many R tutorials out there. This one aims to be a jump start to get you to know exactly what you need to start using R while ignoring all the stuff that you can quickly search for.
As for many topics, tools, and trades, getting the feel of things and figuring out the way they work is the first step. Everything else is the details, so to speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Sweden with R - Fun with Statistikmyndigheten</title>
      <link>/post/2022-03-06-using-r-with-statistikmyndigheten-swedish-statistical-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-03-06-using-r-with-statistikmyndigheten-swedish-statistical-data/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the R package pxweb which facilitates access to public statistical data in Sweden.As with many officially-run sites providing public data,navigating menus and manually downloading files can be cumbersome,much better to gain access with an API where you can download data directly and start using it.However,just mentioning the word “API” may scare away a few folks,so coming across packages like pxweb is always a refreshing discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello. My name is Nick and this is my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
