<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nick Christie on Nick</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nick Christie on Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Swedish statistical data with R - Fun with Statistikmyndigheten</title>
      <link>/post/2022-03-06-using-r-with-statistikmyndigheten-swedish-statistical-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-03-06-using-r-with-statistikmyndigheten-swedish-statistical-data/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the R package pxweb which facilitates access to public statistical data in Sweden.As with many officially-run sites providing public data,navigating menus and manually downloading files can be cumbersome,much better to gain access with an API where you can download data directly and start using it.However,just mentioning the word “API” may scare away a few folks,so coming across packages like pxweb is always a refreshing discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R</title>
      <link>/learn/2021-12-20-introduction-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learn/2021-12-20-introduction-to-r/</guid>
      <description>Why R?
It&amp;rsquo;s a common question. Why would you invest in a new thing when you already have your own thing going?
 It&amp;rsquo;s free It&amp;rsquo;s free You can automate things You can have your entire workflow in one program  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello. My name is Nick and this is my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Introduction to R</title>
      <link>/learn/quick-introduction-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learn/quick-introduction-to-r/</guid>
      <description>There are many R tutorials out there. This one aims to be a jump start to get you to know exactly what you need to start using R while ignoring all the stuff that you can quickly search for.
As for many topics, tools, and trades, getting the feel of things and figuring out the way they work is the first step. Everything else is the details, so to speak.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
